<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scraping on Bruno V. Ribeiro - Home</title>
    <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/tags/scraping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scraping on Bruno V. Ribeiro - Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/tags/scraping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project Toys: Exploring toys descriptions according to gender</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projecttoys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projecttoys/</guid>
      <description>Motivation 👨‍👧 I have a small (super cute) daughter. With children&amp;rsquo;s day arriving here in Brazil she was bombarded with all kinds of toys commercials in all possible media. Being in the &amp;ldquo;asking about everything&amp;rdquo; phase, she made a long list of questions regarding the toys she saw in these commercials and I was just fascinated by the amount and depth of them! Here are some of them:
  🤷‍♀️ Why do all girls toys look the same?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project ATLA: Exploring transcripts from Avatar: The Last Airbender</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectatla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectatla/</guid>
      <description>In this project I scrape the transcripts from the popular show Avatar: The Last Airbender from the fandom wiki. With this data, I do some basic EDA focusing on the character lines. I also included in this project the transcripts from The Legend of Korra. As a fun side project I build a classifier to identify lines corresponding to Aang or Korra. With this, we can put up an app to explore the data and let users input some text to predict if they &amp;ldquo;sound like&amp;rdquo; Aang or Korra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Games: Metacritic Video Games data and recommender</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectgames/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectgames/</guid>
      <description>In this project I collect data from Metacritic to do some basic EDA and build a content-based recommender system. The final recommender is deployed using Dash and all coding is done in Python.
Scraping games info from metacritic The scraper is found on scraper.ipynb. Requires requests, bs4.BeautifulSoup, re and pandas.
The final dataset is on file games-data.csv.
We will use Metacritic data to create a dataframe with data on games across all platforms and all time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Ludopedia: exploring relations between boardgames artists</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectludo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectludo/</guid>
      <description>In this project we will go through our collected data from Ludopedia ranking of boardgames. We&amp;rsquo;ll perform basic data cleaning and EDA.
The data was collected using the Scrapy framework. The scraper is found inside the scraper folder. The relevant files in this folder are:
 ludo/ludo/items.py: defines the features we&amp;rsquo;ll extract from the website. ludo/ludo/spiders/ludospider.py: defines the paths of each item of each game.  The final data set is pre-saved ins this repository under the name ludo/ludo/all_pages2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
