<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Bruno V. Ribeiro - Home</title>
    <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Bruno V. Ribeiro - Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project ATLA: Exploring transcripts from Avatar: The Last Airbender</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectatla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectatla/</guid>
      <description>In this project I scrape the transcripts from the popular show Avatar: The Last Airbender from the fandom wiki. With this data, I do some basic EDA focusing on the character lines. I also included in this project the transcripts from The Legend of Korra. As a fun side project I build a classifier to identify lines corresponding to Aang or Korra. With this, we can put up an app to explore the data and let users input some text to predict if they &amp;ldquo;sound like&amp;rdquo; Aang or Korra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Mushrooms: Fun with the mushroom dataset</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectmushroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectmushroom/</guid>
      <description>In this project we dig into the mushroom data set. With very simple algorithms (decision trees) we can archive that sweet 100% accuracy. To make the experience more fun, a streamlit app is created that let&amp;rsquo;s you control a few hyperparameters of the model to see how you can maximize accuracy. If you reach 100% you get some cool balloons (yay!).
The mushroom data set has been contributed to the UCI Machine Learning over 30 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Games: Metacritic Video Games data and recommender</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectgames/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectgames/</guid>
      <description>In this project I collect data from Metacritic to do some basic EDA and build a content-based recommender system. The final recommender is deployed using Dash and all coding is done in Python.
Scraping games info from metacritic The scraper is found on scraper.ipynb. Requires requests, bs4.BeautifulSoup, re and pandas.
The final dataset is on file games-data.csv.
We will use Metacritic data to create a dataframe with data on games across all platforms and all time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Ludopedia: exploring relations between boardgames artists</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectludo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectludo/</guid>
      <description>In this project we will go through our collected data from Ludopedia ranking of boardgames. We&amp;rsquo;ll perform basic data cleaning and EDA.
The data was collected using the Scrapy framework. The scraper is found inside the scraper folder. The relevant files in this folder are:
 ludo/ludo/items.py: defines the features we&amp;rsquo;ll extract from the website. ludo/ludo/spiders/ludospider.py: defines the paths of each item of each game.  The final data set is pre-saved ins this repository under the name ludo/ludo/all_pages2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Healthy: Eating habits and COVID-19 impact</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projecthealthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projecthealthy/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I use data from food intake by countries along with data associated with the spread of COVID-19 and other health issues to help get new insights into the importance of nutrition and eating habits to combat spreading diseases.
Data for this project is taken from this very interesting kaggle dataset. From the owner of the dataset:
 In this dataset, I have combined data of different types of food, world population obesity and undernourished rate, and global COVID-19 cases count from around the world in order to learn more about how a healthy eating style could help combat the Corona Virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Epidemic Models: Basic Epidemic models done in Python</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectepmodels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectepmodels/</guid>
      <description>In this fun project we explore the most basic mathematical models for epidemiology: the SIR and the SEIR models Read the Wikipedia on these.
The SIR model is implemented in OO style with options for integration with simple Euler scheme or with a second order Runge-Kutta scheme. Besides this straight integration, we implement a Gillespie algorithm to run stochastic experiments here. As this is a variant of a dynamic Monte Carlo method, we can run various experiments using multiprocessing (from the multiprocessing python library).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
