<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EDA on Bruno V. Ribeiro - Home</title>
    <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/tags/eda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EDA on Bruno V. Ribeiro - Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/tags/eda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project ATLA: Exploring transcripts from Avatar: The Last Airbender</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectatla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectatla/</guid>
      <description>In this project I scrape the transcripts from the popular show Avatar: The Last Airbender from the fandom wiki. With this data, I do some basic EDA focusing on the character lines. I also included in this project the transcripts from The Legend of Korra. As a fun side project I build a classifier to identify lines corresponding to Aang or Korra. With this, we can put up an app to explore the data and let users input some text to predict if they &amp;ldquo;sound like&amp;rdquo; Aang or Korra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Mushrooms: Fun with the mushroom dataset</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectmushroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projectmushroom/</guid>
      <description>In this project we dig into the mushroom data set. With very simple algorithms (decision trees) we can archive that sweet 100% accuracy. To make the experience more fun, a streamlit app is created that let&amp;rsquo;s you control a few hyperparameters of the model to see how you can maximize accuracy. If you reach 100% you get some cool balloons (yay!).
The mushroom data set has been contributed to the UCI Machine Learning over 30 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Healthy: Eating habits and COVID-19 impact</title>
      <link>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projecthealthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunobvr.github.io/my_portfolio/post/projecthealthy/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I use data from food intake by countries along with data associated with the spread of COVID-19 and other health issues to help get new insights into the importance of nutrition and eating habits to combat spreading diseases.
Data for this project is taken from this very interesting kaggle dataset. From the owner of the dataset:
 In this dataset, I have combined data of different types of food, world population obesity and undernourished rate, and global COVID-19 cases count from around the world in order to learn more about how a healthy eating style could help combat the Corona Virus.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
